in this Tasker session we are going to
talk about the key box window operation
now this is one of the t-box automation
tools modules
and using this module you can send
specific commands to a particular window
these are mostly useful for window based
applications and we are going to look at
some of the operations which you can
perform
there are lots of different operations
which this module provides like you can
bring the window to front you can close
the window maximize minimize move to
Center normal which is restoring the
window to its original size you can
resize the window you can check whether
that particular window is open or not
and then wait on close and wait on open
right so these are all the different
operations which you can perform using
this particular module we are not going
to look at all of them but we'll be
looking at some of them which could be
useful when you are working with this
windows in your automation test suit
okay
so for this particular example I'm going
to use a
the notepad Okay and as you can see I
have already created a particular test
case called window operations and inside
that my first step is to start or open
the notepad
now if you remember we have talked about
process operations where you can have
the where you can use the t-box Start
program and that's what I'm using I have
given the path which is the notepad path
and when I'm going to run this it is
just going to open the notepad for me
okay so
okay so the notepad is open we have used
the t-box Start program right it's not
part of the window operations but this
is required in order to open this
particular application okay
and then now I'm going to add few other
steps which are related to the window
operations module okay
and we are going to use the t-box window
operation
so let's search for this
right and there are basically four
parameters here or
um that's the values which you can pass
right so you can pass a caption a
caption is nothing but a name for that
particular window okay then window index
if you have multiple windows open you
can put a index to it
and then the operation the operation
which I was talking about there are lots
of operations but uh we are going to use
some of them and this operation is a
drop down list okay so you can see uh we
talked about bring to front close
maximize minimize
um resize move to Center and verify
window access so all of these operations
are present here which you can perform
on your window
okay
so uh coming to caption right so in this
caption
this is a notepad right so the text is
notepad on this particular window but
there is also a Untitled text in this
right so what we can do we can use some
regular expression so that even if the
text changes it will always be able to
identify with this particular caption
okay
although I have got just one window open
right now I can still use a index
um for instance if there are other
windows open for notepad then this will
only consider the first index okay
and then coming to operation right so
what we are going to do first is we are
going to maximize it right
so let's rename this to maximize
okay
now what I can do I can
copy and paste this okay and I can just
change the operation now I will change
it to minimize so it will minimize that
particular window
okay and the caption and window index
will still remain the same
and then let's copy this again we'll try
to use some operations
and then I will say we can bring that or
to the normal size okay
so let's change it to normal
okay and then um in this final step we
are going to close this particular
window okay
and I'm going to use another operation
here okay but I'm going to drag this to
the beginning
okay here
um I'm going to say bring to front right
so if
it is somewhere in the background then
it is going to bring it to the front
Okay so we are going to use this
operation
and that will be all the steps which
will be
um or all the operations which will be
performing using this window operation
module you can try out all the remaining
options but these are the ones uh which
we can try right now okay now let's try
and run all of these different
operations on our notepad right before
that I'm just going to adjust this
particular operation I'm just going to
put it after minimize so that when it is
minimized you can bring that particular
window to the front right and if I run
this whole test case together you might
not be able to see anything because it
will be too fast so what I'm going to do
is I'm going to execute a step one step
at a time right so first I'm going to
execute the maximize so that the window
is maximized
right you can see uh the window size is
not changed it is uh to the maximum
maximum screen size
right
and let's go back here and the
scratchbook you can see it is passed now
let's try and run the minimize window
and the window will be minimized right
and let me put the scratch book uh to a
second window so that we can see that
okay
right uh now let's try and run uh the
bring to front because our window is
minimized
let's try and do that so you can see now
it is showing it in front right
and then let's
run this normal operation so that it
will bring back the window to its normal
size okay
and then finally we'll close the
application
and you will see that uh the notepad is
closed now okay so these are all the
operations uh which can be performed on
a window you can try out all the
remaining operations which I showed you
um on the same window or a different
window
so it's a quite useful module if you
want to perform some operations on a
particular window especially window
based applications
and that's all for this particular t-box
window operation module
foreign